And welcome to week four, day three.
4주 차, 3일째에 잘 오셨어요
As we are about to embark upon another business project which will add real commercial value.
또 다른 사업 프로젝트에 착수할 참이거든요 상업적 가치를 더할 프로젝트죠
It's going to be an exciting project.
신나는 프로젝트가 될 거예요
It's going to be a difficult challenge, and we're going to have, as always, a blast doing it.
어려운 도전이 될 거예요 하지만 언제나처럼 즐거운 경험이 되겠죠
Let's get started.
Get it, Get it, 시작하시죠
So first of all, just a recap of all the things you can do this time I'm going to let you read it,
먼저, 여러분이 이번에 할 수 있는 모든 것의 요약입니다 여러분이 읽으실 수 있게 해드리죠
but after today you're going to be able to assess models for coding ability and use frontier models
하지만 오늘 이후엔 코딩 능력을 위한 모델을 평가하고 코드 생성을 위해 LM을 사용하는
to generate code building a solution that uses Llms for code generation.
솔루션을 코드 구축하기 위해 개척자 모델을 사용할 수 있게 될 거예요
And of course, it's going to include a user interface.
물론 사용자 인터페이스를 포함하죠
It's going to include a lot of the bits and pieces to package it up nicely to be an app.
앱으로 잘 패키지하기 위해 많은 비트 조각들을 포함하고 있어요
So a quick reminder of the challenge.
과제를 다시 알려드릴게요
We want to build a tool that can convert Python to C plus plus for performance.
파이썬 을 C++로 변환하는 툴을 만들고자 합니다 성능을 위해서요
And this time today we're going to do a frontier model solution.
오늘은 개척자 모델 솔루션을 해볼게요
Next time we're going to add open source models as we battle the the frontier closed source versus open
다음엔 오픈 소스 모델을 추가하겠습니다 개척지 폐쇄 소스와 오픈 소스에서 싸우면서
source and see what wins out.
뭐가 이기는지 보죠
Uh, first, just a quick a quick explanation of what we're going to do.
먼저, 우리가 할 일에 대해 간단히 설명할게요
So we're going to prompt our models with a prompt that explains what we want them to re-implement Python
모델에 뭘 재구성하길 원하는지 프롬프트할 거예요 파이썬 코드와 C+를요
Plus.
더 있어요
Um, it's maybe going to be a little bit more wordy than this one, but it'll be along these lines,
이것보다 좀 더 장황할 수도 있지만 이런 내용입니다
uh, trying to convince the model not to do any explanation, just simply to provide the C plus plus
모델을 설득하는 거죠 어떤 설명도 하지 말고 그냥 C 플러스 플러스 코드를 제공하라고요
And its objective should be to do whatever it takes to run faster and give the same output.
그리고 목표는 어떻게 해서든 더 빨리 달리고 같은 출력을 내는 것이어야 하죠
But otherwise, the world is its oyster.
그것만 빼면 세상은 그의 굴이에요
It can do what it wants, it just has to give the same output.
원하는 건 뭐든 할 수 있어요 같은 출력만 주면 되죠
And this is a bit of code that we'll start with to try out in Python.
파이썬 을 테스트하기 위해 비트 코드로 시작할게요
Uh, you may know already that there is a series which very slowly converges to a nice number, and
이미 아시겠지만 일렬로 나뉘는 숫자가 서서히 하나의 큰 숫자로 모입니다. 일렬은
that series is one minus a third plus a fifth, minus a seventh plus a ninth, minus 11th, and so on.
1 빼기 3분의 1 더하기 5분의 1 빼기 7분의 1 더하기 9분의 1 빼기 11분의 1 이렇게 이어지죠.
You get the idea.
Get it, Get it 아시겠죠?
Uh, if you keep that series going and you multiply the result by four, you gradually converge on pi.
어, 연속성을 유지하면서 4를 곱하면 점차 파이의 수렴이 되죠
But it takes a very long time.
하지만 시간이 오래 걸려요
And so we can run it for the first 100 million iterations, and we will actually get quite close to
그래서 처음 1억 번 반복할 수 있고 그 시점에서 파이에 꽤 근접하게 되죠 get
pi at that point.
it
But you'd have to do an awful lot of typing on your calculator to to do 100 million iterations.
하지만 1억 개의 반복을 하려면 계산기에 엄청나게 많은 타자를 쳐야 해요
Uh, but Python will do it reasonably fast.
파이썬 을 이용하면 꽤 빠르게 할 수 있어요
But we'll be hoping that C plus plus can do it a whole lot faster, and that Frontier models will help
C 플러스 모델들이 훨씬 더 빨리 할 수 있길 바라요 프런티어 모델들이 도움될 거예요 Get it, Get it,
us get there.
Get it
Let's find out.
알아보죠